Hello,
David. How we doing? Can you hear me? I can hear you well. Good. Uh,
well thanks for, uh, booking the call real quick. How did you,
how did you find us? Oh, beautiful.
I've had this for years.
Nice. So you've been, uh, you've been,
I've been aware of you guys for quite a while actually. Yeah. Perfect.
Yeah, I'd love to hear that. Book's a couple years old.
We're actually working on, uh, version 2.0 of it, so stay tuned.
Yep. Yeah, absolutely. Yeah. Now I've had the book for a while.
We've always managed our, our, uh, ss e o in-house,
but I'm at the point where I'm just sort of exhausted from doing it.
We're kind of flat lining for a while now,
so I'm just finally gonna bite the bullet and
not build an internal team and look to partner with someone who
Okay. Kind of
Is a philosophy kind of thing. Right,
Okay. No, for sure. Okay, so let's start there. So tell me a little bit about,
so I, I have atress looking over here,
so it does look like you guys get a decent amount of traffic, right?
A pretty good amount. Looks like some solid keywords,
but it does look like it's plateaued over
Oh, yeah.
A couple year period. Yeah. So what, what, what did,
what did you do for the spike?
And then talk to me about what you're doing on ongoing kind of maintenance
basis.
Uh, well, so basically,
um, it's focusing on keywords and long, long tail keywords,
mostly is what we do. And trying, I've used kind of a,
the, uh, you know, the pillar page type model, um Sure.
With kind of hub pages and then, you know, linking back,
internal linking out to those. So we've kind of been doing that for a while now.
Um, and yeah, I, I just sort of flatlined like, uh,
the spike, the big spike was years ago, and then it kind of,
kind of gone up and down. A lot of it was, I didn't have a real consistent,
um, a consistent kind of publishing and things like that and upkeep. Mm-hmm.
So I've had a content manager now for, I don't know when she's,
she's less than a year now,
but it's been the best we've had in terms of like focusing on our core
keywords, trying to pare down duplicate content, you know, um,
and just having consistent content basically. So it's been a big boon for,
for that.
Okay. But
Even then, I've noticed it's sort of, even with that,
it's still kind of plateauing. I mean, I think our, our problem is links,
but I'm hoping you guys can tell me what our problem is.
Yeah, we'll, we'll figure that out. Um, so in regards to this,
this content manager, is this person also writing, writing the content for you?
Yeah. Yep. So what, what I hired her write at a journalism school.
Okay. Nice. Um, and how long has she been on board for?
She's been on, it's less than a year.
Okay. And before, before that, were you, you were writing all the content?
I was writing all the, the content mostly. Yeah. I had a content manager,
like a, a year, a, a while back from there, but that one was not good at all.
Uh, it's like I know a good how good the Lisa one is, but yeah,
it was mostly me doing the content and then it was like, you know what?
It's like, it's boom bust, you write some, then you're working,
you don't do anything. So it wasn't consistent. Yeah. Um, so with her,
she's writing a lot of the content now and I'm just sort of like,
she's interviewing me. Then we'll write the piece. Um,
I do weekly webinars as kind of lead generation, so she'll attend those.
I'll do a topic and then she'll write articles off of the content from that.
Um, you
Said weekly webinars?
Yeah. Okay.
Yeah. Love it. Um, and
Yeah, we do a lot of things right. But with,
there's just these core things around the ss e o that I just feel like I need
outside help
Finding for sure. So, so in regards to, so again,
just clicking through like that, I do agree. You're doing a lot of stuff right?
The content looks great. I was actually gonna say,
it looks like you're keeping it updated too, which is another thing. Yeah.
Right. I'm a big fan of with
Her. There we are. Yeah.
Yeah. A lot of law firms, especially will overextend themselves on keywords,
right. Go after things that are just too top funnel and then just create,
create, create, and stack up bad content.
And then right over time they'll lose that visibility for the key keywords.
So we always suggest more of like a,
define the content universe in terms of keywords that we think are gonna drive
business value, and then just keep iterating and keeping those fresh. Right. Um,
so I love that. So, and in regards to the webinars too, how are,
how are you promoting those? Email list?
Email list? Yeah.
Okay. How big is the email list?
Uh, it's a little over 2000.
Okay. And what type of people are you?
Like who, like what, what,
what does a target target person look like on the other end
Target person? For us, we do just disability cases.
So it's social security disability type cases,
but our bread and butter is like long-term disability insurance cases.
So it would be professionals,
people working in companies who have long-term disability insurance and then get
sick and have to take time off work.
Okay.
Yeah. And everyone on our list is come through our kind of funnel lead magnets.
They've all kind of opted in and ordered one of our books.
So this kind of thing. Yes.
Okay. Um, and in regards to the data,
yeah.
So like in terms of leads from organic on a monthly basis,
do you have that? Are you tracking that? Yeah.
Yeah. Got it. In ss e m rush,
What, how many, how many leads are you currently getting from, from Morgan?
Oh, leads a month. Yeah. Um, boy, I, I could, uh,
I could tell you that. I just have to look it up. We set our meeting,
I should know it. But yeah, I, I have all that data. We track it all,
we track the full conversion pipeline of it so we know how many perfect leads,
how many are good leads,
and then how many set for appointments and all that kind of stuff.
But I have all that.
Okay. Yeah, I, I would love to dig into that with you. Right. Because, you know,
a lot of what we try and do here, obviously we're,
we're very well versed in organic search,
but what I always try and impart on our prospects is that we use search because
right now it's the best way to generate leads for law firms. Right.
For the near foreseeable future. Maybe that,
that might start to change as AI starts to take over. Right. Right. As
Kind of worried about that too, I dunno how,
And we can talk about that too.
I'm happy to give you some thoughts and opinion on towards the end of this. Um,
just remind me. But, you know, at the end of the day,
we'd like to say that we're, we're, we're,
we solve acquisition problems for law firms. Right. And again,
search is the best mechanism to do that.
So I do like to talk about the specific data in terms of current leads getting,
and then also target leads. Right. So, and really just backing out,
just in terms of a,
a projected r o i and also just projected marketing program that this is your
first time out basically. I, I don't call it outsourcing right.
'cause we're more of a partner than just like, you know, just dumping this
On top. Yeah. But it pretty much is. Yeah. Um,
Yeah. You know, this is your first time doing it.
I wanna make sure that we're clear on the goals. Clear on the numbers. So, um,
in terms of, in terms of the sales off the back end of it, do you take all the,
all the calls?
Yes.
Okay. So no matter what happens, we do
Have an overflow, but they just book appointments with our sales reps,
basically.
So you do have sales reps?
I do, yeah. I have two.
Okay. How many, how many reps do you have?
Two. Two
Reps. Two reps. Yeah. And are they working,
is that like an outsource company that you hired to just take phone calls on
screen? They work for full time internal.
Yep. Yep.
And they're both pretty high level at this point and they've had a lot of sales
training.
Good. I love it.
Yeah. Now they're complaining more about a lot of the low quality leads,
but kind of told 'em you gotta, that's part of the game, right? Yeah.
I always tell clients it's, it's good. I love talking to you because you're,
most attorneys are,
you're light years ahead of most law firms in terms of your marketing knowledge
and understanding. Um, you know, and there's always pushback.
One of the biggest rebuttals that I get on just marketing in general from law
firms is like, oh, well there's so many tire kickers. And I'm like, look,
50% of everyone that walks in your door setting on fire,
it's just not gonna work. It's just the way the internet is,
especially when it comes to levels of qualification.
That's why I was asking about the person, because, because it kind of vari,
we can't really dial in on a specific avatar for a lot of law firms. Right.
You know? Yeah. So it's difficult to do social media ads 'cause it's like,
who are we targeting? Well,
we're just gonna put a digital banner up with great messaging and see what comes
in. Similar to going offline search is really the only way that we can qualify
people. 'cause they're putting themselves in market by searching for it, right?
Yep. Exactly. But even still, even still, you know,
you just get a lot of tire kickers. People just wanna ask questions. Um,
and it's good because most law firms struggle with the sales process too.
They insist on taking every call, which I get because, you know, they,
you're the verified expert they wanna talk to. Similar with, with our business.
Oh, I don't do any calls anymore. Good. I I got outta that years ago. Yeah.
So I don't do any consultations myself anymore unless it's a real corner case,
like a very high value and there's something unique about it. But yeah.
So, so would you say then, is your goal here then a spec?
Because we don't have the numbers to look at, which we don't have to.
That's okay. Would you say your goal is a specific number of leads to provide,
like, you're getting 50 now, you want to get to a hundred?
Or is this more of a I just search is just take is a vi is a viable channel
for us. We know that it's just taking too much of my time and I'm looking to,
to partner up with, what would you say? No,
It's, it's, it's a little bit of both. Like search,
I feel like search has always been my bread and butter,
like for the last decade. And I feel like we're, I'm not,
I we should be totally leading the market and we're not. Okay. So,
and I've noticed that it's kind of plateaued. So I,
I know there's things that we need to be doing that I'm just not,
I don't want to manage it anymore in terms of knowing the ideas and here's what
we wanna do. Um, but yeah, ultimately I want to max out our, our,
uh, our leads coming from search. Yep.
Okay.
Search is our bread and butter. Uh, I've dabbled around in everything else.
I don't have, I don't have, uh, paid campaigns right now,
but I probably would go back to it.
That's what I was gonna ask about too. Yeah, yeah.
Yeah. I would go back to it at some point. I just, I kind of paused it.
I did have an agency for that and it just was not,
there was not a good return on investment on it. Mm-hmm. Um, but
So
I recognize that there's a branding element to it and just
It's that, and it's also like what I would, without digging too much into it,
and just looking at the level that you're operating at now from an ss e o point
of view. Right. Sorry, my dog might barks my wife. I don't, um, got. Oh no.
Um, so what I would, when I take a deeper look at this,
we'll talk about towards the end of this call,
like what I'm probably gonna pitch to you is some sort of paid search first.
Mm-hmm. Before diving full into SS e o. The reason being, 'cause it looks like,
like you, if you engage in an outside agency off somebody else,
a lot of what we're gonna be doing is looking at keywords and viability.
It seems like you have a really good handle on that. Right?
So for us to come in and be like,
we're gonna do queue research and create new content, it's like, well,
we can pass that over to us for sure. But search ss e o just takes so long.
But with paid search, what we can do is test new keywords, right?
So like a paid discovery for keywords.
So if we shift the goal into a place where we're looking at using paid search
to test viability to then create ss e o value,
that's probably what I would push you for.
Kind of like a rev ops style of approach to this. Where again,
it's real like,
aside from going into keyword tools and creating content around it,
like it's the fastest and most effective way to create.
'cause it seems like content's been working you for, for a while. Right.
And if you're plateauing, not because you're losing rankings,
which we'll look into just because you've just kind of tapped on what you can
talk about, then paid search becomes very, very,
very impactful from a discovery and also a conversion point of view too,
because we're very, very good at getting the cost down. Um,
so in terms of that though, what is your average,
like what is your average client worth to you?
Yeah, so we have three types of, three classes of clients.
So long-term disability clients are 16,000.
Um, that's the gross, like that's not, that's mm-hmm.
That's our, that's our fees on it basically. Uh,
our social security cases are around 6,000,
so they're a lot less room there for.
And then we do one other type of case that I'm really not trying to grow that
much, but a workers' comp type case. Those,
I'm still trying to dial in what they're worth,
but they're worth probably closer to like 10,000.
Okay. So obviously in terms of priority, it's Yeah. Long-term disability,
social security, and then workers' comp.
Yeah, I've had the content managers spoken exclusively on,
I'm trying to really expand the long-term disability and we've noticed kind of a
drop off in leads on those cor like from our, from our tracking. So Okay.
I'm trying to determine why. Um,
and whether it's just more competition. Are we dropping on certain pages, um,
where we're kind of, where we're dropping the ball on that.
Okay. Uh, I'll figure that out for you. No worries. Um,
what are you using to track?
Is this an an Google analytics based tracking system or do you have a good third
party software that's tracking?
We use, uh, so we do all our s we do all our, uh, we, we use SS e m Rush,
we got Google Analytics, but for the sales stuff, it's um, uh,
active campaign.
Okay, nice. So you're using that as a C R M
C R M and email management. Yeah. Perfect. But we have,
we've got the sales process built pretty well out in it.
Yeah. I use active, our
Conversions are, our conversion process is really good.
And I am meeting with one of the sales reps who's in charge of that.
Like that is, we're gonna dial it in more, but that's dialed in pretty good.
Our, we kind of have a lead problem at this point.
Okay. Okay. Good. That's good to know. Um, okay. Do you have,
do you have any questions for me? Um, just based on what we talked about,
anything else?
No, no. I've, I've, uh,
I know a lot about you just because like I said, I read your book. I've,
I've watched a lot of stuff.
I like your kind of approach of the sprint model and really trying that type of
idea. Um, and I'm just, I need someone else to look at this, kick the tires.
It's, and realize like I'm not a SS e o expert.
I've been doing it for a long time. Um, but I'm, I don't want to,
I don't want to build a, I don't want to be, I want,
I'm kind of sick of dealing with it quite honestly.
I understand in terms of like trying to keep up on it.
I'd rather talk to someone.
I know enough that I can have a conversation about it,
but I don't want to have to try to,
and I am kind of worried about the chat G P T and that type of search is,
that's gonna really potential to just upend the whole game, right?
Yeah. Let's talk about that for a second.
So it's gonna be twofold with law firms, right?
One is gonna be the automation internally, right? So like doing discovery,
not sure how much you do that at your firm, but like discovery type processes,
right? Like gone next in the next year or two, right?
I dunno if you've seen what the company's called. Do not pay. Have you,
I dunno if you've seen what they're doing worth Googling. They actually,
I saw to their c e o is like a PR guru man. He know,
he knows how to tap into this vein right now. Basically,
they sent out like a press release saying that they were anybody who has a
Supreme Court case that Oh yeah,
I've seen that million bucks to argue the case on your behalf. Right? Um,
so a lot of that stuff, and, and again,
like this is gonna happen across industries,
I think it's gonna be especially harmful to the legal industry because of
the fact that it's so oversaturated right now with the amount of the volume of
kids coming out of law law school, right.
Into a place now where there's gonna be no entry level jobs for the most part.
Yeah. It's going to,
it's gonna really bra thoses principle 80 20 just eviscerate,
I think like 80% of the law firm market. Same thing with agencies though, right?
Like yeah, there's a lot of, I mean, just like anything in, in,
in life in business and economics, when when we get comfortable and we get,
yeah, it's, there's a trimming of fat needed, right?
It's gonna open up massive opportunities for humans.
I think humans will be okay,
but I do think it's gonna massively disrupt business industries and just really
trim the fat on just bloated firms or, you know,
small firms, unfortunately. Right? Um, I we're
So reliant on the, right now, we're so reliant on pa our, uh,
search like that is, that is our whole lead that that's 90%
Of our Yeah. And that, and that's the other part of it too, right?
Which is gonna be the marketing element of it,
which I'm obviously very in tune with. And what I think is gonna happen is this,
I think search is also going to be impacted dramatically just in terms of volume
traffic going to websites, right? When we look at things like,
I don't know, the nuances of like workers' comp law,
like comparing different cases or whatever it looks like, right?
The AI within search engines are gonna demolish like content traffic, right?
Yeah. But, but, and this is where I like,
am really pushing a lot of my thought energy and just kind of like
trying to, to read the tea leaves,
but Google's not gonna blow up their own business model, right?
Like they make all their money,
all their a hundred billion dollars a year off of pay-per-click ads, right?
They cannot blow that up, right? So what I think is gonna happen is that yes,
content is gonna be like, again,
this is another example of trimming of the facts because I think so much of
content that's created is not helpful.
It's garbage and like it has no business value.
So we actually started heavily pushing paid search because what we're now
looking at is what we're calling a blended search model, right? Mm-hmm.
Meaning focusing a lot of people, a lot, especially agencies, they got lazy.
They took a top-down approach. Let's find the biggest keywords.
Let's create content around it's easy. Get it to rank, drive traffic,
but not business results. We're now saying we need to take a bottom-up approach.
We need to start with the heaviest,
heaviest he intent keywords and then look at it and say, and this is a future,
but like what we're doing now is a gap analysis saying, okay,
what's the best way to get visibility and traction for this keyword?
Should we do an L s A for a local service ad? Should we do PCL ad?
Should we build a video or,
so we're starting to map it to look at like what's the best way to attack this
search engine is just a communication tool, right? Whether it's social,
whatever, like,
so I think that then in the future we're gonna have to layer on another level of
analysis saying, okay, is this an AI query that ai we, no one's gonna, like,
it'll cite your website as a source from it, but like,
is it worth us spending energy on content anymore?
'cause AI is just gonna cannibalize that. I agree. So
I think there's always room for authority though. If you can establish those,
establish an authority. That's why I do the books and things trying to really,
And that's, that's why you're gonna be okay. Yeah. And I really mean that,
right?
Because people who take the time just like myself to create thought to opinion
is the other big factor here, right? Yeah.
So like we're talking about the commoditization of content c commoditizing
opinion is gonna be very difficult. And if you just look at media now too,
I mean, it's outta control, especially in the states, right?
You're lucky you're in Canada. Um, yeah. Like the, the the,
how they've just driven a stake down this country and split us in half and have
us fighting with each other over
The same thing here on a slightly lower scale, but it's, yeah,
very similar here. Same issue. Yeah.
It's just, it's human nature, right? So they're,
they're playing on this opinion, but you know,
applying that to business which matters here. Agreed.
Thought leadership matters. And that's what I was saying too, when it comes to,
we tie all this together, right? Yeah.
There's still gonna be plenty of opportunity.
Like people are still gonna be lawyers, you know, but they're gonna, yep.
When it comes to the AI stuff, they're gonna lean towards people like yourself.
That's like, yo David, you know, comes from referrals. I read his book,
I saw him on like, it's in the same thing, just a much smaller market,
but probably in in smaller demand too. But still maybe more demand. So again,
it's gonna be a squeezing of the market just like it's gonna be on search
engines. But like I think that if you approach it the right way,
at the end of the day,
like law firms are still gonna exist and law firms are still gonna still need
customers.
And that's why I said too is that right now we use search 'cause it's the best,
but like maybe AI becomes an actual option for us to get visibility for our
clients there as well. Yeah. And that's what we're gonna be all in on, right?
So that's kind of my approach to everything. Um,
I got into law right on the cusp of the inter like lawyers.
Like I had one of the first lawyer blogs in North America,
like I got in right at that point when I got into law outta law school and I saw
how it upended everything, right? Yeah. Like a hundred percent.
I kind of think we're on the, uh, verge of that. Again,
one of my biggest assets is I have a print newsletter list of like
close to 3000 people that I send a print newsletter out every month.
Nice. I like it.
That is like gold. It really, I know it's kind of old school,
but it's all people who opted in for books and things. Like,
it's very much very community oriented and things like that. Like they're very,
it's a very engaged audience, believe it or not, on a newsletter. A
Hundred percent.
And and that's actually also where I think like the final part of this is that
like what I think is gonna make a major comeback is things that people know
are human driven that took time and care. Yes. Right?
Because like a return to craftsmanship if you will, right? Yeah.
So that's a good example of that, right? A return to human creativity,
things that are like truly handmade. We see it now.
People pay a certain more amount for things that are handmade versus mass
produced, right? Yeah.
So there's certain things as humans that are a little bit predictable and I
think that's one of them, which is a good thing, right?
Is that the businesses that take the time, and this is what it boils down to,
the businesses that put in the energy that care about their clients more than
anything in the world and care about getting them,
what they come there for are the ones that are gonna win.
Which is the same thing now. We've just gotten very,
very fortunate and bloated with the amount of success that's happened over the
last 20, 30 years through the internet.
That's just created a lot of fat and I think it's just gonna get trimmed down.
So again, I think folks like yourself, it's not something,
it's good to be thinking about it,
but it's not something you have to worry about per se.
'cause like you're already light years ahead of most law firms that I talk to
that are like ai, what's that?
Yeah, yeah, their website. Like that's the thing. Like the, my website doesn't,
maybe I definitely,
like we could be getting a lot more traffic and we could be
doing better, I believe. I don't think we're maxed out on the paid, uh, on the,
definitely not on the paid, but on the, on the search aspect,
I feel like there's some, some things, things I'm missing here, but, um,
but yeah, no, that, that's, uh,
That's why we're here. That sounds good. So, so in terms of next steps,
so part one is this quick discovery call. Yep. I think it's a great fit.
Definitely a lot of things that we can add value to with step two we'll have our
analysis call in between then and now. We'll, we'll do a deep, a deep analysis.
I don't need access to analytics. I'll look at EMR arus and do a topal analysis.
Yeah.
Try and figure out maybe why you're stagnant and then also put together some
thoughts in terms of growth. Um, yeah,
there'll be some thoughts about paid organic different strategies. Also, again,
like stuff with webinar, there's,
there's a whole bunch of things that probably more on the consulting basis that
we could help you with, right. In terms of providing,
like another business that I have is like a fractional C M O business where
essentially it's kind of like serve as the backbone of,
of all the marketing and everything kind of runs through us,
but if you have the execution pieces,
then we can help take a lot of load off your plate. So, um,
final question though,
because I'll put together kind of a scope and a quote off the back of this.
Was there,
is there a budget mine that you just did not want to go over on a monthly basis?
Um, there's not, not, not really. No.
Okay. 'cause I can go nuts here.
Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Well like I would say like I saw on your website kind of the ranges you had
there. Yeah. I think it was somewhere it's the low end was four,
it went up to 10 or something like that.
So like that's kind of the range I'm looking at. Okay,
Perfect. Yep, that's right where we live, so. Okay, cool.
So last thing is I just wanna get this booked in for our follow call. Uh,
Friday or Monday will work for me if you have either of those open.
I'm free on Friday aft anytime after 12 noon.
Okay.
Between 12 and four noon. I'm in Eastern time.
Yeah, you're in Eastern. Okay. I'm one hour. What am I, I'm Atlantic,
so I'm one right now. It's five o'clock basically where I'm at.
So you're four o'clock just talking
Four o'clock. Yep, exactly. Yep. Would
You be able to do something at uh, three o'clock my time?
What would that be for you?
Two o'clock, 2:00 PM my time? Yep. Yeah,
That work?
Yep. Perfect. I'll send over that invite now.
Okay, perfect. Um, yeah, so we'll chat on Friday by, in that,
by that time we'll have, you know, high level analysis done.
We'll read the notes and just feels like a good fit then. Um, you know,
we can talk about a proposal to, to work together.
Alright man. Awesome. Good to
Meet you. Great chatting you David. We'll talk soon. Yep. Take care. Bye-Bye.